Hi, it's YouTube scam time. Now, this is
not a regular debunking video. It
actually involves a whole bunch of like
big name YouTubers who have been
taking a sponsorship from a company
called Established Titles and also
Kamikoto knives as well. And you might
have you know, seen the in video
sponsorship thing. This video sponsored
by Established Titles or whatever. And
there it turns out that it's a scam.
Basically, and a whole bunch of
prominent YouTubers have
like taken the sponsorship money and you
know,
almost certainly with good faith, of
course. So, don't blame them for taking
it cuz as YouTubers, we have to make a
living. I personally don't take any of
these sponsorship ones. Haven't taken a
single one in 13 years, but I'm not in
the same situation as other YouTubers.
I've got other income sources that I can
rely on. But certainly if YouTube was my
only income source, then yeah, I'd
probably have to have in video
sponsorship as well. So, I'd be looking
at taking these sorts of deals. Anyway,
in the last 24 hours, there's been a
video from Scott Shafer here. I haven't
seen his channel before. But he's done
an excellent video. I'll link it in up
here and down below. Highly recommend
you men you watch it. I won't go over
all of the details that he's basically a
three step process to debunking this
thing, this Established Titles company
as a scam. Anyway,
here's a list of like some of the
prominent YouTubers that have been
caught up. You know, Ben Shapiro,
Phil Phil DeFranco is a big name,
you know, Matt Walsh and like David
Pakman Show and you know, like there's
most of them I haven't heard of cuz I'm
not in this space. Anyway, there's a
whole bunch of YouTubers that have done
in video sponsorships for Established
Titles and also Kamikoto knives who are
also basically owned by the same company
and there might be other
companies as well. But anyway, watch
Scott's video. What is this established
titles thing? Well, very quick recap
here. It's basically this company owns
it turns out it's a Hong Kong based
company owns a block of land in Scotland
and they claim to be able to sell you.
Here it is you can become a lord or lady
or whatever.
You know, you get a and you get like a
framed certificate. I'm a lord or I'm a
lady because they'll sell you one square
foot of land in like a Scotland. And it
turns out that not only are they a Hong
Kong company, but it turns out that
legally no, you don't own the land and
no legally you can't become a lord or
lady. So it's one of these like vanity
kind of scams where they'll sell you a
fake certificate or whatever. You know,
you buy like a you can get it like an
asteroid named after you or something.
You know, there's there's like tons of
these sorts of you know, scam vanity
scam I guess you could call them around.
But yeah, as it turns out no, you can't
call yourself a lord or lady. It's just
it's just BS. Right? And it turns out
that if you watch
Scott's video over here, he talks about
how they have like a countdown timer on
the site to make it look like you know,
you've got X time left. It looks like
they've actually removed this. So it
looks like some change and we'll see
later some changes have been made in
response to this
you know, debunking of this thing in the
last 24 hours. But it turns out that
this isn't the first time
that
it's it's been you know, people have
talked about the scam. If you type in
type in established title scam into
YouTube, there's actually this simply
explained video here is a good one. That
was from a month ago. He's only got 141
subscribers. So it didn't get much
reach. Maybe though all those videos
came recently. The biggest there's
Scott's video there, but here's one four
days ago like and two years ago from
someone called Neil. Can you really
become a Scottish lord established
established titles scam. So it's not you
know, hard to sort of find whether or
not this is legit. So, anyway, normally
I wouldn't do a video on this because
it's already been done, but I've
actually they actually approached me and
I've got some additional information
which is not in Scott's video. So, let's
go through this. So, they actually
contacted me and you can see here I've
wiped out the email name and the phone
number and stuff and the person
involved, but here it is. This is what
all us YouTubers get all the time. Like
practically daily we get one of these
sponsorship emails and and I usually
just, you know, straight to the
spam, you know, hit the spam button, but
if they do actually say, "Hey, if they
usually include my name in there, hey
Dave, hey David", then I'm going to like
give them a personal reply. In this
particular case I just replied with,
"Sorry, not interested." YouTubers get
these all the time. "Establish ties to
project, blah, blah, blah." Yeah, it's a
fun novelty gift. So, they're even in in
here they say it's like a novelty gift.
So, it's, you know, it's a novelty. So,
I
up front they're kind of like a little
bit honest.
They're they're honest liars. So, this
was back in September. Anyway, they they
wanted to pay me 450 bucks which isn't
much
for something like this. It's it's not.
Like I've turned down $5,000 offers for
sponsorship for one video. So, yeah, it
depends on the niche you're in and that
kind of thing, but yeah, anyway, like
some of the top YouTubers they'll be
getting paid a lot more than that
$5,000, I'm sure. Anyway, they usually
want a 60-second or 90-second YouTube
integration here. Now, it comes from a
company called Galton Voicey.com
and this is quite common. YouTubers will
get these sponsorship deals from
advertising agencies and they're they
can be like legitimate huge advertising
agencies which big companies go through
to, you know, talk to us influencers to
do the deal and they take a, you know,
50% cut or whatever it is, like a huge
uh cut. And yeah, basically the
middleman between the uh creator and the
company that wants to advertise. So, you
know, right off the bat, it looks like
like it's not from Established Titles.
It's from Galton Voicy.com. So, let's go
and have a look at who Galton Voicy is.
Like, it sounds like a
advertising agency, doesn't it? So,
anyway, we go over here. Here we go. We
are the alliance of independent brands.
Uh who are we? Talent team of mavericks
who come together to build a worlds
leading direct-to-consumer e-commerce
leading direct to consumer brands. We do
this by building, acquiring, and
partnering with e-commerce brands. Uh
but once again, right up front, like you
don't have to do any detective work.
They actually tell you if you went to
the effort to go to the website, we
currently have five DTC brands that we
own 100%.
Um
guess which brand they own 100%?
So, there's no link on this website that
I can find to which brands that they
actually own, but I think you already
guessed. But the interesting part is, of
course, we go over to the culture and
team over here, and they don't try to
hide any of this, okay? So, this is all
out there, right? So, here's all the
people running this, okay? So, these two
names here, William Wolfram and Katerina
Yip, these two seem to be the main ones
involved in all of these companies,
including Katerina Yip is the owner of
Established Titles. In fact, if you go
over here, there we go, Established
Titles was founded by Katerina Yip.
There you go. So, yeah,
so they also own Not only do they own
this what appears like, you know, to a
YouTuber at a casual glance, appears
like just yet another
you know, marketing agency you're being
contacted by, but they actually own all
of these titles. And in Scott's video,
anyway, basically,
look, they they own this other company,
it's a venture capital company called
Fail Ventures, ironically, right? It's
Fail Ventures. Fail Ventures is unique.
We're fast We're fast at failing now.
So, they've founded 78 new ventures from
scra- scratch and six have succeeded,
right? And in Scott's one, actually,
this website also seems to have changed,
cuz if you go over to where Scott's
video here, he shows you their website
here, which seems to have changed,
unless I'm on a different website. They
own DealDash, which is dodgy in its own
right. And look, here's this Galton
Voicy here. It's actually there.
Kamikoto Knives and Established Titles.
So, all the YouTubers doing Kamikoto
Knives and Established Titles are being
contacted by Galton Voicy here. And it's
just one big circle jerk, right? By this
couple in Hong Kong. And there's other
people like Ringo Wong here. He's also a
co-founder. And surprise, surprise,
there he is there. So, yeah, you can see
that, right? And all these same people
are all across these companies. And
there's probably even more to this, as
well. So, all these people, they're all
just form these companies. You see this
again and again with these venture
capital people. And these You know, they
set up these companies that get the
latest fad, the latest scam, or whatever
it is
in in this particular case. And they
have all
You know, marketing wank behind it.
Right? So, all of these same people,
they're all tied together. And you don't
have to go far down the rabbit hole.
It's all in their company websites. It's
all on their LinkedIn. And if you just
do a cursory
examination of the companies that you're
dealing with in this particular case. I
didn't bother going further at the time.
I just said, "Yeah, nah, thanks. Not
interested." But yeah, if like if I was
accepting a sponsorship opportunity,
then yeah, I'd at least, you know, check
out the company. And maybe
this is some incentive to YouTubers Is
it going the rabbit hole just a little
bit deeper and seeing if, you know, how
any companies are tied together and
their reputation may, you know, as
something as simple as like typing in
as, you know, established titles scam.
And you can see this video going back 2
years, right? There it is. Um yeah, so
it's just I once again, I don't blame
the YouTubers and please don't blame any
of your YouTubers. Don't stop, you know,
subscribing or following just because
they, you know,
promoted this um scam thing. It's just
They're just trying to make a living.
And it sounded pretty good cuz I'll
actually show you also, which uh Scott
didn't show you. I can show you that the
pack that they actually sent you. It's
only a brief one, but here's the They
give you this uh PDF. And this is very
common for, you know, these companies.
They will have these uh you know, media
packs which they send to the, you know,
influencers that uh want to sponsor, you
know, about established titles. So, they
give you some background and then what
campaign they want. We'd love it if you
can touch on our main talking points.
Sometimes they'll give you the talking
points and and when you do a video,
you'll have to give it to them for
approval and they go, "Yep, you've met
all our talking points." And that sort
of, you know, stuff cuz they're, you
know, paying money. So, usually they
just don't leave it up to you. They will
want to like sign off on the videos. So,
here's some sample ad integrations and
stuff like that. Often they'll like
point to other YouTubers. Yeah, look at
that Cinema Therapy. I don't know. I
haven't heard of them, but they Yeah, it
looks like they link over to YouTube
videos. So, you can go in there and
watch it and then it all looks legit.
So, you can see other legit YouTubers
are like, you know, doing this then it,
you know, you
wouldn't necessarily think to sort of
like investigate any further cuz it all
sounds legit. Especially when it comes
from what looks like, like, you know, a
typical, you know, high-end media
marketing company kind of thing. But you
don't know that they're all intimately
tied together. It's It's all just one
big circle jerk um sell this established
titles scam. So, this is a very brief
one. Some are much more detailed than
this, but this is typically what the
influencers will get and they'll give
examples and it's all very well done.
It's all very professionally done. So,
you can't blame really. I can't blame
any YouTubers for um falling for this
sort of thing. But anyway, um hats off
to um Scott and the other people who've
uh debunked this. I just thought I'd add
something extra there. And the other
thing that the Simply Explained uh video
did here, apparently they've had the
number of uh you know, the amount of
money raised cuz apparently they'll
plant a tree for every person who buys
one of these established uh titles thing
and then they just they don't actually
plant the tree. They just uh use some
third-party company. They just
supposedly pay them and uh that's you
know, to plant this tree and apparently
that's a legitimate organization. But of
course, you can just give your money
straight to the company who plants the
tree. So, anyway, um
anyway, he found that uh yeah, this
figure that they had uh planted you
know, planted all the money that they
raised to actually plant these trees.
So, he discovered in the Wayback
Archives that this was figure was always
the same, 42,000 uh pounds raised or
whatever. So, if we go and have a look
at um the current one raised, how much
have they raised? It's suddenly Look at
this, they've added a ticker there. It's
suddenly um they've planted at least one
tree over 2 million trees planted in
Scotland around the world where most
needed. One one tree planted or
something is the company. So, they've
changed that. So, they've changed it
from $42,000 donated to apparently 2
million if you believe it. 2 million
trees uh planted or whatever. So, yeah,
they they just changed their website and
they don't have the countdown timer on
there anymore. So, it looks less scammy
and stuff like that. So, I think clearly
they've actually tried to make some
changes since this has all come to
light. Yeah, this uh
marketing um team is also owned by them
in one gigantic circle jerk.
Unbelievable. Anyway, thoughts and
comments down below. Catch you next
time.